那边那位
Hello there!
你好啊
Hello!
你好
Hello?
Hello!
-你在做什么  -我刚才在设陷阱
- What are you doing? - I was setting a trap.
-陷阱  -在你家房顶
- A trap? - On your roof.
-然后呢  -我亲自试了试
- What happened? - I tried it out.
-怎么会  -一不小心
- How? - Accidentally.
-保佑你  -谢谢
- Bless you. - Thanks.
-你叫什么  -格兰特
- What's your name? - Grant.
-你好  格兰特  这是几楼  -60楼
- Hello, Grant. What floor is this? - 60.
-我能进你家吗  -我得问下我妈
- Would it be all right if I came in? - I will have to ask my mom.
妈妈  醒醒
Mom, wake up.
妈妈说你可以进来
Mom says you can come in.
我们知道你会来
You're expected.
知道我会来
Expected?
抱歉  你是说你们知道我会来吗
Sorry. Did you say I was expected?
是啊
Yeah.
你跟她说我是谁了
Who did you say I was?
我跟她说窗外有个老公公
I told her I saw an old guy at the window.
圣诞快乐  格兰特
Merry Christmas, Grant!
爸爸妈妈都睡着了
Mom and Dad are asleep now.
我可以把你送回房顶
I can get you back on the roof.
我知道怎么上去
I know the way.
-你在做什么  -看看那张图
- What are you doing? - Take a look at that picture.
-看完了  -然后看这张
- OK. - Now this one.
好好看看  要看一会儿才能发现
Take a good, long look. It takes a moment to see it.
发现什么
See what?
超人和克拉克・肯特是同一个人
Superman and Clark Kent are one and the same person.
-你是认真的吗  -是
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
看  我给超人画了副眼镜
Look, I drew specs on Superman.
大家都知道他俩是同一个人
Everyone knows they're the same person.
露易丝・莱恩可不知道
Well, Lois Lane doesn't.
她还是名记者
And she's a reporter.
为什么人们叫他蜘蛛侠  都不喜欢他吗
Why did they call him Spider-Man? Don't they like him?
他被一只放射性蜘蛛咬了
He was bitten by a radioactive spider,
你猜之后怎么了
and guess what happened?
我猜是放射性元素中毒
Radiation poisoning, I should think.
不对  他获得了超能力
No, he got special powers.
什么能力  呕吐  脱发和死亡吗
What, vomiting, hair loss and death?
半点用没有
Fat lot of use.
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
-它看上去  -我懂
- That looks... - I know.
廉价
Cheap.
闭嘴
Oh, shut up!
你感冒了吗  格兰特
Got a cold there, Grant?
我圣诞时总会感冒
I always get a cold at Christmas.
我也是  或是有人入侵时
Me too. Or an invasion.
-你从哪弄来的  -口袋里
- Where did you get that from? - My pocket.
-你怎么把一杯水放口袋里的  -有技巧
- How do you keep a glass of water in your pocket? - Skills.
现在安静  我有很多事要忙  拿着这个
Now, hush. I've got a lot of work to do. Take this.
-你是谁  -博士[医生]
- Who are you? - The Doctor.
-我知道  但你是谁  -博士
- Yes, but who are you? - The Doctor.
哪个医生  有很多医生呢
Which one, though? There's lots of doctors.
就那个
THE one.
最主要最初的那个  我是第一个叫这个的
The main one, the original. I started it.
他们都是模仿我
They're all based on me.
现在想让自己听上去很聪明的人都自称博士
Now everyone who wants to sound clever calls themselves Doctor.
成了时尚
Bandwagon!
你知道在漫画书里你会叫什么吗
In a comic book, you know what you'd be called?
神秘医生[博士]
Doctor Mysterio!
我喜欢这个
I like that.
神秘博士[医生]
Doctor Mysterio!
这个名字我收了
I'll have that!
差不多好了
Nearly ready.
这是什么
What is it?
用你能懂的说法来讲
Well, in terms that you would understand...
抱歉  不存在你懂的说法
Sorry, there aren't any.
它是  它是
It's a... it's a... it's a...
它类似时间扭曲均衡器
it's a time-distortion equaliser thingy.
什么
A what?
在纽约有很多小型扭曲点
There's been a lot of localised disruption here in New York,
所以...  其实那都是我的错
so... my fault, actually.
希望这个能修正它们
Hopefully this will make it all calm down.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你知道什么是避雷针吗
Do you know what a lightning conductor is?
-知道  -它和避雷针不一样
- Yeah. - Well, it's not like that.
我以为你是在设陷阱
I thought you were setting a trap.
我是在设  为了保护它
I was. To protect this.
我不希望有人关掉它
I don't want anyone turning it off,
或者偷走它当圣诞树
or stealing it for a Christmas tree.
但它看着就像圣诞树
But it looks like a Christmas tree.
当然像  这是科学
Of course it does, it's science!
-你想把灯都点亮吗  -可以吗
- Do you want to turn the lights on? - Can I?
去吧  今天是圣诞
Go on. It's Christmas Day.
我要怎么做
What do I do?
把它放进这里
Put this into this.
然后把这些小开关都打开
And you flick all those little switches on.
什么都没发生
Nothing's happening.
是  因为现在才是有趣环节  来
Yeah, because now we get to the cool bit. Come here.
看见那扇小门了吗  打开它
Do you see that little door there? Pop it open.
现在我们要点灯了
Now we turn on the lights.
把宝石放在这里
Pop the gemstone right in there.
什么宝石
What gemstone?
我给你的那颗  放到这里
The gemstone that I gave you - pop it right in there.
那是颗宝石
That was a gemstone?
它可不止是颗宝石
Well, it's more than a gemstone -
它类似嵌入式电脑  过来
it's also like a kind of onboard computer. Come here.
你能  你能看到那颗黄色的小星星吗
Can you see... Can you see that little yellow star
那条弧线尽头的那颗
at the end of that curve?
它来自那个地方附近
It comes from near there.
成型于红洞的正中
Formed in the heart of a red hole
稳定后成为纯净的矮星晶体
and stabilised in pure dwarf star crystal!
那宝石有感知  它知道你的愿望
The gemstone is intuitive - it knows what you want
然后从最近的行星获取能量来实现它
and draws energy from the nearest star to make it happen.
全宇宙只剩下四颗
There's only four of them left in the universe.
安多拉的天启僧
The Apocalypse Monks of the Andorax
将这一颗称为  哈赞卓
called this one the Hazandra
爱与愿望之灵
the Ghost of Love and Wishes.
好了  把它放进去吧
OK, then. Pop it in.
我以为它是药
I thought it was medicine.
什么
What?
它看着像一颗药
It looked like medicine.
你把它怎么了
What have you done with it?
你给了我药  还给了我水
Well, you gave me medicine and a glass of water,
你还说你是个医生[博士]
and you said you were a doctor.
我以为是治我的咳嗽的
I thought it was for my cough.
你吞了它
You swallowed it?
你不能随便吞东西啊  你多大了  36吗
You can't go round swallowing things! What age are you, 36?
八岁
Eight.
我是要生病了吗
Am I going to get sick?
不不不  正相反
No, no, no - quite the opposite!
相反  相反是什么意思
The opposite? What's the opposite?
-发生什么了  -没事
- What happened? - Nothing.
我怎么了
What's wrong with me?
你得了感冒  还悬浮起来一点点
Well, you've got a cough and a slight case of levitation.
-冷静  -如果我不冷静会怎样
- Stay calm. - What happens if I don't stay calm?
-别慌  -如果我慌了会怎样
- Don't panic. - What happens if I panic?
没事没事
You're all right!
好宝宝
You're OK!
喂  伦巴德夫人
Hey, Mrs Lombard.
没事  别担心  詹妮弗很好
No, don't worry, Jennifer's fine.
她刚醒  我这就哄她继续睡
She just woke up, but I'm going to put her back to sleep.
没事  伦巴德夫人
No, it's OK, Mrs Lombard.
你花钱就是雇我做这些的
It's what you pay me for.
好的  晚安
OK. Goodnight.
格兰特  你得集中注意力
Grant, you need to concentrate.
我怎么了
What's happened to me?
会感知的晶体  外加过多的漫画书
Intuitive crystal, plus too many comic books.
宝石在给你它觉得的你想要的一切
The gemstone is giving you what it thinks you want.
你成超级英雄了
You're a superhero...
今天之后的所有问题
Any questions after today
将由舒斯特或西格尔小姐解答
can be handled by Miss Shuster or Miss Siegel,
大家可以在欢迎礼包里找到
who can be contacted on the e-mail addresses
她们的邮箱联系方式
provided in your welcome pack.
今天到此为止  女士们先生们
That's all we have time for, ladies and gentlemen.
希望你们度过了很受启迪的一天
I hope you had a stimulating day,
也看到是什么让和谐浅滩
and maybe saw a little of what makes Harmony Shoal
成为当今世上最好的科技改革者
the foremost innovator in science and technology the world over.
正如我们常说的  我们在此开拓你的眼界
Like we always say - we're here to open your minds.
布洛克先生  最后一个问题
Mr Brock, just one more question.
我有调查过你的资金动向
I've been looking into your funding,
作为研究机构  你似乎有很多捐助人
and you seem to have a lot of benefactors for a research institute.
世界在变  弗莱彻小姐  科学更吸引人了
The world is changing, Miss Fletcher. Science got sexy.
是  但你的捐助人  我一个也找不到
Yeah, but your benefactors - I can't seem to find any of them.
原因很简单
Very simple reason for that.
我把他们都杀了  埋在我家后院
I killed them all, buried them in my back yard.
你家后院有多大  布洛克先生
How big is your back yard, Mr Brock?
上次算的时候有怀俄明州那么大
At the last count, Wyoming.
如果诸位不介意的话
Now, if you good people will excuse me,
这位女士将送诸位至出口
this young lady will guide you to the exit...
布洛克先生
Mr Brock?
Er, Mr Brock?
布洛克先生  布洛克先生
Mr Brock? Mr Brock.
显然  这位还有一个问题
Apparently we have one more question.
是的  请问男厕在哪儿
Yes. Where's the little boys' room?
你可以在出去路上的左侧找到洗手间
I think you'll find the restrooms to the left, on your way out.
不  不是休息室  是男厕
No, not the restrooms, the little boys' room.
如果你成功找到'休息室'
If you successfully locate the restrooms,
在那儿你能找到所需的一切
I think you'll find everything you need in there.
-谢谢各位  -女士们先生们  请这边走
- Thank you all. - This way, ladies and gentlemen.
我又不想休息
I don't want a rest.
如果大家都只是去休息  我会搞出事情的
If everyone's just having a rest, I might cause an incident.
辛姆博士  有问题吗
Dr Sim, is there a problem?
是那些大脑  我有东西要给你看
It's the brains. There's something I need to show you.
-很必要  -晚些时候再说
- It's necessary. - Later.
咱们午夜在这里见
Meet me here... At midnight.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
布洛克先生  你吓到我了
Mr Brock. You startled me.
咱们走吧
Shall we?
好的
Of course.
没人了
All clear!
怎么了
Well?
看看它们  你没看出异常吗
Look at them. You see nothing unusual?
我看到了脑子
I see brains...
到处都是  除了你脑瓜里
every place except here.
这些标本是我们的捐助者捐赠到这里的
These specimens were donated to this facility by our benefactors,
为的是一个高度机密的研究项目
for a top-secret research project.
这个项目不可被质疑  妨碍
A project which is not to be questioned, impeded,
甚至不能和任何
or in fact mentioned by any of the employees
和谐浅滩研究院的职员提及
of the Harmony Shoal Institute.
就连我都没有权限知道这里的事情
Even I don't have the clearance to know what's going on in here.
-但为什么  -你的工作不是问问题
- But why? - It's not your job to ask questions!
专注研究就行了
Stick to science.
你的眼睛出问题了吗
Something wrong with your eyes?
先生  第一次来时我数出来24个标本
Sir, the first time I came in here, I counted 24 specimens.
第二次我数时有30个  现在有36个
The second time I counted, there were 30. Now there are 36.
我猜是他们腾出地方了吧
Well, I guess they've got the space.
你没懂  没有任何物流记录
You don't understand. There have been no deliveries.
我查过了
I checked it.
这里有些大脑  先生  它们就这么
Some of these brains, sir, they just...
凭空出现了
Arrived.
没事  我也是闯入者
It's OK. I'm an intruder too.
没错  我带了零食  专业人士的标志
Yeah, I brought snacks - mark of a pro.
继续听
Keep listening.
我看着就是个大脑
Looks like a brain to me.
有点蓝  但是是因为液体的缘故对吧
Kind of blue, I guess, but that's the fluid, right?
对  是那液体
Yes. That's the fluid.
敲一下玻璃  先生
Tap the glass, sir.
-你说什么  -请敲一下玻璃
- What did you say? - Tap the glass. Please.
这到底是  什么东西
What... the hell is that?
这是开玩笑吗
Is that a joke?
不  先生  这不是玩笑
No, sir, it's not a joke.
它长了眼睛  看看  它们就像是
It's got eyes! Look at them, they're like...
它们像是你的眼睛
They're like your eyes.
是的  先生  一点不错
Yes, sir, they are.
辛姆博士
Dr Sim?
-你在指什么  -我指的是辛姆博士
- What are you pointing at? - I'm pointing at Dr Sim.
别那么紧张  我们交换了容器而已
Don't look so alarmed - we merely exchanged containers.
你可以管这个叫  劫持
You might call this a... hijack.
你怎么了  我不明白
What happened to you? I don't understand.
同样的事将会发生在你身上
The same thing that is about to happen to you.
我改变想法了
I had a change of mind.
不不  求你  不要
No! No, please, no!
放我出去
Let me out of here!
怎么回事  你们要干什么
What's happening? What are you doing?
你是谁
Who are you?
露西・弗莱彻  《每日纪事报》记者
Lucy Fletcher, reporter from the Daily Chronicle.
等等  我为什么会跟你说实话
Hang on, why am I telling you the truth?
惊奇吧  想弄个大新闻吗
Spooky, isn't it?  Looking for a story?
我想我刚找到一个
I think I just found one.
有独立思想的大脑们
Brains with minds of their own?
没人会相信的  这里是美国
No-one will believe that - this is America.
你是谁啊
Who are you?
特工丹・戴泽瑞斯  来自苏格兰场
Special Agent Dan Dangerous from Scotland Yard,
苏格兰
Scotland.
简称博士
The Doctor for short.
你看  他们世界各地都有分部
See, they've got institutes all over the world.
而且都在首都
And always in capital cities.
不是
Nope.
是的  是的  没错的  你看嘛
Yes, yes, they are, see?
纽约不是首都对吧
New York's not a capital city, is it?
你不需要指出错误
You don't need to point out the mistakes.
你不是来干这个的
That's not what you're for.
华盛顿也有自己的分部
Washington's got its own one.
我本想叫保安  但他们可能会饶你们不死
I would call Security, but they might leave you alive.
我不想面对关于我为自保
I do not want any awkward questions about intruders
不得不射杀闯入者的麻烦问题
I was forced to shoot for my own protection.
好计划  我这也有一个
Good plan. Here's another one!
来啊  告诉他们你在自卫时从背后杀了我们
Go on. Tell them you shot us in the back in self-defence.
我们会笑着入土的
We'll be laughing all the way to the slab.
-面向我  -不了吧
- Face me. - Maybe not.
立刻面向我
Face me now.
那是什么声音
What is that?
-不是我  -听起来像是
- It's not me. - It sounds like...
像是某人在敲玻璃
Like someone knocking at a window.
我们在100层啊
We're on the 100th floor.
-我的天  他真的存在  -谁真的存在
- Oh, my God, he's real. - Who's real?
-超灵  -超灵是谁
- The Ghost. - Who's the Ghost?
-蒙面义务警员  但他是  -什么
- Masked vigilante. But he's... - What?
超人
Super.
-不介意我进来吧  -真厉害
- Mind if I come in? - Impressive.
这些窗户  和这建筑里的所有东西一样
Those windows, like everything in this building,
被建造得足以抵挡住
are built to withstand a blast
相当于四颗核弹爆炸的冲击力
equivalent to four nuclear explosions.
真抱歉  需要我叫装玻璃的工人吗
Sorry about that. Would you like me to call a glazier?
请理解  我个人准则不允许我
Please understand, it's against my personal code
对个体造成持久性伤害
to cause lasting harm to any individual.
但是轻度到中度伤害是没问题的
However, light to moderate injury is fine.
真不错
That's good!
你好  这个人有骚扰到你吗
Hello. Was that man annoying you?
你是真的  我不敢相信  你是真的
You're real. I can't believe it, you're actually real.
恐怕是的  我喜欢你的专栏  弗莱彻小姐
I'm afraid I am. I enjoy your column, Miss Fletcher.
你看我的专栏吗  你看报
You read my column? You read?
你是真的  而且你还看报吗
You're real and you read?
不过我觉得你社评论里的政治倾向
Though I find the political bias in your paper's editorial
不太合我口味
not entirely to my taste.
-我会转达的  -谢谢
- I'll pass that on. - Thank you.
这几位是谁
Who are these gentlemen?
他们是  我其实不知道
They're, um... I don't actually know.
-这是我朋友  纳多尔  -你好  超灵
- This is my friend, Nardole. - Hello, the Ghost!
而我是博士
And I'm the Doctor.
博士
The Doctor.
我们有不少的博士
I thought we had lots of doctors.
我是唯一的
I'm the main one.
-我能送你回家吗  -你有车吗
- Can I give you a ride home? - You have a car?
不
No.
-我希望你不恐高  -目前还好
- I hope you're OK with heights. - I'm OK so far!
祝你们晚上愉快  先生们
Have a good evening, gentlemen.
他  看起来不错
He... seems nice!
格兰特
Grant...
所以我现在是超级英雄了吗
So I'm a superhero now?
只要你身体里的宝石没了
Once the gemstone is gone from inside you,
你就会变成普通人了
you'll be back to normal.
-会过去的  -但是它要怎么出来啊
- It will pass. - But how will it get out?
就像我说的  会过去的
Like I said, it will pass.
你就等着吧
Looking forward to that.
-你肯定吗  -我当然不肯定了
- Are you sure? - Of course I'm not sure.
没有什么是绝对肯定的
Nothing's ever sure.
向我保证一件事
Just promise me one thing -
只要你还有这些能力
for as long as you have these powers,
你就永远  绝对不会用它们
you will never, ever use them.
好的
Sure.
是这栋楼吗
Is this the right building?
从天上看它们都一个样
They all look the same from up there.
对对  到这儿就好了  谢谢
Yeah, yeah, this is me, thanks.
我衷心希望这场不愉快的经历
Well, I certainly hope this unpleasant experience
没让你对新闻工作心生厌烦
hasn't put you off a career in journalism.
不  不  一点也没有
Oh, no, no, no. Not at all.
抱歉  有新任务
Sorry. Duty calls.
天哪  蝙蝠信号已经做成应用了吗
Look at that. The Bat-Signal's an app now?
是什么事  银行抢劫  劫机
What is it? Bank robbery? Hijack?
差不多吧
Something like that.
先走一步
Excuse me!
上吧
Go get 'em!
能力越大  责任越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
担得起那样名号的人不该把婴儿独自留在家
No man worthy of the title leaves a baby alone.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我追踪了你体内的宝石
I tracked the gemstone inside you.
你的能力不属于这个世界
Your powers, they don't belong in this world.
那些能力都是不正常的
They're an anomaly.
你答应过我永远不使用的
You promised me you'd never use them.
-我来抱着她吧  -她是你的孩子吗
- May I take her? - She's yours?
我是她的  我是她的保姆
I'm hers. I'm her nanny.
你是她的保姆
You're her nanny?
对  她的保姆  有什么问题吗
Yeah, her nanny. You got a problem with that?
没有  只不过
No, no, it's just...
这么说你既是超级英雄又是保姆
OK, so you are a superhero and a nanny.
谁都得想办法挣钱糊口
You've got to make a buck somehow.
救人可拿不到钱
You don't get paid for saving people.
跟我们说又没用  给  温好的
You don't have to tell us. Here you go, nice and warm.
很好喝  大象
And tasty! Ooh, elephant!
没事的  我有远距离婴儿监视器
It's fine. It's a long-range baby-monitor.
我赶回这间公寓的速度
I can get back to this apartment
比大多数人到婴儿房的速度还快
quicker than most people can get to their kids' bedrooms.
格兰特  格兰特  这太荒唐了
Grant, Grant, this is insane.
看  我就是我  博士
Look, I'm me, the Doctor,
连我都觉得太荒唐
and even I think this is insane.
-连他都这么觉得  -我应付得来
- Even him! - I can cope.
你肯定不行
Of course you can't.
你什么时候睡觉  你什么时候不随叫随到
When do you sleep? When are you not on call?
你想把生活搞得多复杂
How complicated do you need your life to be?
没接下来那么复杂就行
Well, not as complicated as it's about to get.
我们在这呢  伦巴德太太
We're in here, Mrs Lombard.
詹妮弗  瞧瞧你  又醒了
Oh, Jennifer, look at you, up again!
你从来不睡觉吗
Don't you ever sleep?
今晚过得愉快吗  伦巴德太太
Did you have a good evening, Mrs Lombard?
是工作的事
Oh, it was work.
有什么好开心的呢
Why would it be good?
不好说  你看起来有点兴奋
Well, I don't know, you seem a little buzzed.
我还以为你遇见了什么人
I thought maybe you'd met someone.
也许遇到了  也许没有
Maybe I did, maybe I didn't.
格兰特
Grant...
你们在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我们也可以这样问你
We could ask you the same question.
但这是你家  所以不大可能这么问
But it's your apartment, so we probably won't.
我们  我们很担心你
We... we were worried about you.
我们想确认一下你没事
We wanted to make sure that you were all right,
所以就跟着你
so we followed you.
你们跟着我却比我先到家
You followed me and got here first?
这只是说明我们有多担心
Well, that's just a measure of our concern.
我们非常担心
Very concerned.
他们说认识你  我就让他们进来了
They said they knew you. I let them in.
我们今晚见过面
We met tonight.
我们得谈谈  你和我
We need to talk, you and me.
出什么事了吗
Did something happen?
不用担心你帅气的小脑袋瓜
Nothing for you to worry your pretty little head about.
-我去哄她睡觉  -可以交给我
- I'll put her to bed. - I can do that.
没事的  我想哄她睡觉
No, it's OK, I want to.
伦巴德是她的夫姓
Lombard's her married name.
孩子生下来后他跑了
He ran off when the baby came along.
露西
Lucy.
当然了
Of course.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我是你代数课的代课老师
I'm your relief algebra teacher
我想该来看看你过得怎样
Thought I'd check in on you, see how you're coping.
还没过去  如果你想知道的是这个的话
Well, it hasn't passed, if that's what you want to know.
我认为那已成为你基因的一部分了
I think that it's a part of your DNA now.
已经和你融为一体了  抱歉
It's bonded with you. I'm sorry.
-你为什么不看着我  -我不想
- Why aren't you looking at me? - I don't want to.
你谁都不看  你变得害羞了吗
You're not looking at anyone. Are you shy now?
地板就那么吸引你吗
Is that floor really interesting?
我不是害羞  我只是没法停止它
I'm not shy. I just can't stop it.
停止什么
Can't stop what?
透视眼
The X-ray vision.
简直太煎熬了  看谁都是裸的
I'm in hell. Naked hell.
我没法看着别人
I just can't look at people!
是宝石  它在对你的青春期作出反应
It's the gemstone. It's responding to... puberty.
-嗨  格兰特  -嗨  露西
- Hey, Grant! - Hey, Lucy!
你真喜欢她  是不是
You really like her, don't you?
我有透视眼  我喜欢所有人
I have X-ray eyes - I like everyone!
-可露西是你最喜欢的  -谁说的
- But Lucy is your favourite. - Who says?
高中毕业几年之后  我再次和她偶遇
'A couple of years after high school, I ran into her again.'
-她甚至还记得我  -你真走运
- She even remembered me. - Oh, that was lucky.
那时我和我最好的朋友在一起
And I was with my best friend at the time,
而她也无法把眼睛从他身上移开
and she couldn't take her eyes off him.
-好吧  -一见钟情
- OK. - Love at first sight.
-是啊  -后来他们结婚生子
- Right. - Then marriage, then a baby...
然后他和别人跑了
and then he ran off with someone else.
我猜  这是好让你
Leaving, I suppose,
-有机会搬进她家  -是啊
- The field open for you to move in... - Yeah.
照顾她和别人生的孩子
and care for the child she'd had by another man.
对
Yeah.
这样她就能继续工作
So she could keep working
还可以和你的其他朋友约会
and possibly date other friends of yours.
-差不多吧  -你牛
- Pretty much. - You tiger.
-谢谢  -你在谢谁
- Thank you. - Who are you thanking?
宇宙
The universe.
有人在这方面比我还差劲
There's somebody worse at this than me.
不好意思
Excuse me.
这是翰傅先生  翰傅先生觉得疼
This is Mr Huffle. Mr Huffle feels pain.
来厨房找我
Meet me in the kitchen.
稍等一下
With you in a minute.
你是苏格兰场[伦敦警察厅代称]派来的
So... you're from Scotland Yard.
是的
Yes.
不告诉我你的秘密也可以
It's fine if you don't tell me your secrets.
我也想保留我的  但不许对我说谎
I intend to keep mine. But don't lie to me.
-否则会怎样  -我会伤害翰傅先生
- Or what? - I hurt Mr Huffle.
我猜你应该是
I assume you belong to some kind of,
某个机构的人
I don't know, agency.
我不在乎具体是哪个机构
I don't care which one,
你现在的任务
and that your current assignment
是调查和谐浅滩研究院  没错吧
is to investigate Harmony Shoal. Correct?
不  我其实只是路过
No, I was just passing through...
好吧  好吧  大体上是这样没错
OK, OK. Yes, fine, OK. Yes, broadly speaking, yes.
那些长得跟大脑一样的东西是什么
What are those brain things?
我不知道  不是你需要关心的事情
I don't know. It's nothing that need concern you.
我是记者  不存在不需要我关心的事
I'm a reporter. That category does not exist.
它们是什么
What are they?
就算我告诉你  你也不会相信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
那就更没理由不告诉我了
No reason not to tell me, then.
那些大脑
Those brains,
不仅仅是大脑
they aren't just brains.
它们是独立的外星人个体
They're independent alien life forms.
然后呢
And...?
它们在星球间迁移
They migrate from planet to planet,
对合适宿主的
extracting and replacing the central nervous systems
中枢神经系统取而代之
of compatible hosts.
然后呢
And...?
和谐浅滩研究院是跨国企业
Harmony Shoal is a multinational corporation
建立它的真正目的是取代
whose true purpose is to extract and replace the brains
全球关键领袖人物的大脑
of key authority figures around the world,
准备对地球进行全面殖民
and prepare Earth for full colonisation.
你相信我吗
You believe me?
我不认为你在说谎  有点不一样
I don't think you're lying, slightly different.
和谐浅滩研究院和超灵有什么关系
What has Harmony Shoal got to do with the Ghost?
-没关系  -所以你知道超灵的身份
- Nothing. - Ah, so you know who the Ghost really is, then?
不  我毫无头绪
No, I have no...
别想再对我说谎
Oh, stop it.
我们刚去了绝密科研机构
We just went to a top-secret science research facility,
显然那里由外星大脑掌管
apparently run by brains from space,
一个有超能力的飞人突然出现
and a flying man with superpowers turns up.
谁都会觉得他们之间有关联
Anybody would assume the two were connected,
除非那个人清楚他们之间没有
except for someone who already knew they weren't.
所以很显然你认识超灵  而且信任他
So, clearly, you know the Ghost, and trust him.
没人会相信自己不认识的人
Nobody trusts anybody without knowing who they are,
所以你知道他的真实身份
so you know who he really is.
现在你可以告诉我  他到底是谁
So now you can tell me. Who is he?
真有趣
Oh, that's interesting.
-你不为某个机构工作对不对  -是吗
- You don't work for an agency, do you? - Don't I?
你不习惯听到这样的语气
You're not used to being spoken to like this,
证明你既没有上司也没有雇员
which means you don't have a boss or an employer.
那你为什么要调查和谐浅滩研究院
So why are you investigating Harmony Shoal?
你想从那里得到什么
What's in it for you?
我不喜欢闲着
I like to keep busy.
为什么  你经历过什么
Why? What happened to you?
没什么
Nothing!
你看
Oh, look!
"因为防火是每位市民应有的责任
'Because fire prevention is the 'responsibility of every citizen
记得要装好烟雾探测器"
'so get a smoke detector!'
"抱歉  有任务了”
'Sorry, duty calls.'
瞧他多忙碌
Oh, look at him go.
我要知道他的真实身份
I need to know who he is.
没事的  她只是要换尿布了
You're all right. She just needs a change.
没事我来吧  你速度真快  格兰特
Oh, it's OK, I'll do it. You're so quick, Grant.
他速度的确很快
Oh, yes. He's definitely quick.
你有休息时间吗
Do you have any time off?
-风暴来临时  -当然
- 'As the storm hit, - Sure!
我们获悉有两名儿童
'it became clear that two children
依然被困在摩天轮上
'were still trapped on the big wheel.
这两名儿童...
'The two small...'
博士
Doctor?
你帮我和他牵线搭桥吗
So, can you put me in touch with him?
和面具后的那个人
The real guy behind the mask?
你很聪明
You're smart.
连我都发现了你有多聪明
You're so clever I actually noticed.
-我都不怎么听别人说话  -所以呢
- I hardly ever listen when other people are talking. - So what?
-所以你为什么不能自己找  -我有线索
- So why can't you find himself yourself? - I got a lead.
什么线索
What lead?
你  你认识他  别再跟我说你不认识
You. You know him. Don't even try telling me you don't.
也许你也认识他
Maybe you know him too.
格兰特去哪了
Hey, where did Grant go?
我在呢  伦巴德夫人
Right here, Mrs Lombard.
-你要喝咖啡吗  -不用了  谢谢
- Would you like your coffee? - Oh, no, I'm OK, thanks.
-你没事吧  -没事  为什么这么问
- Are you all right? - Sure, why?
你好像有点湿
You're kind of wet.
就是这么柔顺
I prefer mild-mannered.
你能帮我和他连上线吗
Can you put me in touch with him?
-超灵吗  -对  超灵
- The Ghost? - Yeah, the Ghost.
伦巴德夫人
Mrs Lombard,
有些事情太愚蠢了
there are some situations which are just too stupid
不该继续下去
to be allowed to continue.
等等
Hang on.
-你好  -是露西・弗莱彻吗
- Hello. - 'Is this Lucy Fletcher?'
我是  请问是哪位
Yes, who is this?
抱歉  我之前得先"飞"一步
'Sorry, I had to fly.'
我是在
Am I...
抱歉  请问你是超灵吗
Sorry, am I... Am I speaking to the Ghost?
你好  露西
'Hello, Lucy.'
我希望这意味着你要接受我的采访
So, I'm hoping this means I'm getting an interview.
采访不是不可能
'An interview is entirely possible,'
但有件事我必须事先声明
but I must make one thing clear.
你不能探究我的真实身份
There must be no talk of who I really am.
你要上头条  规矩你说了算
You make the headlines, you make the rules.
谈论我的真实身份
Discussion of my true identity...
会让我最亲近的人置身危险
would put the people closest to me at risk.
-我不能接受  -那倒是  我明白
- That is not acceptable. - Fair enough, get that.
那明晚如何
How about tomorrow night?
做什么
For what?
专访啊
The interview?
-我们可以共进晚餐  -晚餐
- We could get dinner. - Dinner?
你需要吃晚餐吗
Do you eat dinner?
-我当然吃晚餐  -那好
- Of course I eat dinner. - OK, then.
明晚来接我  八点怎样
Pick me up here tomorrow night, um, eight o'clock?
我在屋顶等你行吗
I'll wait for you on the roof?
等等
Wait a second.
格兰特  你明晚能帮我看宝宝吗
Grant, could you babysit for me tomorrow night?
拜托了  这很重要
Please, it's important.
-我有个约会  -我有个约会
- I've got a date. - I've got a date.
-约会吗  -约会吗
- A date? - A date?
-差不多吧  -好吧
- Kind of a date. - OK.
只是专访
An interview.
你  在和谁约会吗
Are you... seeing someone?
这和我无关  我是说
None of my business. I mean...
但是  你有吗
But are you?
我是说  你从不出门  突然就有对象了
I mean, you never even go out, and suddenly you've got a date?
对我来说也是个惊喜
Yeah, well, it kind of came as a surprise to me too.
-什么意思  -一言难尽
- I'm sorry? - It's complicated.
我可以作证这真是一言难尽
I can confirm that it's definitely complicated.
别担心  我会照看詹妮弗的
You know, don't worry about it, I'll look after Jennifer.
-真的吗  -真的吗
- You will? - You will?
我会想办法的
I'll figure it out.
交给我吧
Let me take care of it.
-好的  -好
- OK. - OK.
-她嫉妒了  -我还嫉妒呢
- She's jealous. - I'm jealous!
格兰特  你在嫉妒你自己
Grant, you were jealous of you.
其实她也在嫉妒她自己
Technically, she's jealous of her.
格兰特  你认识她多久了
Grant, how long have you known this woman?
从小学就认识了
Since elementary school.
整整24年
24 years.
都24年了吗
24 years?
也是  当然都过去这么久了
Yeah, of course it would be that.
你没事吧
Are you OK?
时间不会为任何人驻足
Time passes for everyone.
对我也一样
Even for me.
拜托  作为人类男性  请你尽你所能
So, please, as much as it is possible for a human male,
别干蠢事
try not to be an idiot.
说真的  你没事吧
No, seriously, are you OK?
我从来都很好
I'm always OK.
欢迎你  兄弟
Welcome, brother.
你的皮囊如何
How is your vehicle?
有点紧
A little cramped.
用用就松弛了
It will relax with wear.
看这个
Observe this.
这个星球上最好的皮囊
The finest vehicle this planet has to offer.
有意思  可以弄到手吗
Interesting. And can it be acquired?
正在制定计划
A plan is being formulated.
这个人
This one.
他是谁
Who is he?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
但他可能是危险人物
But he may be dangerous.
他看上去不像
He doesn't look dangerous.
我正在连线跟你们对话
I'm talking to you live!
就在这里
In person!
你们可以回到自己的皮囊里去了
You can jump back in your skins now,
当然  除非这不是你们的  是不是
except, of course, they're not your skins, are they?
-你想要什么  -慈悲
- What do you want? - Mercy.
我们没有这种东西
We have none.
这不是请求  是提议
It's not a request, it's an offer.
我让你们先来
I'll give you a head start.
我会闭上眼数到十
I'll close my eyes and I'll count to ten.
我不会试图跟着你们  但从现在起
I will make no attempt to follow you but, starting now,
你们在全球的所有人
all of you, everywhere,
给我收拾收拾  滚出这个星球
pack your bags and get off of this planet.
你是在对我们宣战吗
Are you declaring war on us?
我只是在划清界限
I am drawing a line,
并且我建议你们速度退到后边去
and I'm suggesting you step back from it with awesome speed.
那就是宣战了
Then war it is.
多核生物
Multi-nucleate organism,
适应性无限强大
functioning as an infinitely adaptable,
独立运作  不断转移的中央神经系统
independently functioning, peripatetic central nervous system.
开着脑壳[能听别人意见]挺不错
Good to keep an open mind.
-当然这完全是无用功  -什么无用功
- Of course it won't work. - What won't work?
不管是什么  无论你们策划了什么
Whatever it is, whatever you've got planned.
就从最明显的开始
Stating the obvious,
你们在世界上所有的首都中建立了据点
you've set up in every capital city in the world,
所以显然你们的计划
so clearly the "Plan"
是撬开世界上所有领导人的脑壳
is to unzip the head of every world leader,
把你们自己放进去
pop yourselves inside.
当然  你们不能堂而皇之的
Of course, you can't just roll up
带着一队外科医生进入白宫或克里姆林宫
with a team of surgeons to the White House or to the Kremlin,
因为它们有大栅栏  大嗓门的人和疯狗
because they've got big fences, shouty people and cross dogs.
他们会来找我们  还是跑着来
They will come to us and they will come running.
我可不这么觉得  拿着这个
I very much doubt it. Take this!
对  拿着
Yes, take that!
你是谁
Who are you?
地球面临过很多次入侵
There have been many attempts to conquer the Earth.
我都数不清了
I've lost count.
但没有一次成功的  一次也没有
Not one of them has succeeded, not a single one.
他们都一败涂地
They all lost and burned
仓皇逃走
and ran.
那就是我
That's who I am.
这是什么
What is this?
是个汉堡  我总会带点零食的
It's a burger. I always bring a snack.
但我现在不想吃了  他影响了我的食欲
But I don't want it now, he's put me off my dinner.
很好  完美定位
Very good. Right on target.
其实就是不断尝试
Trial and error, to be honest.
在途中意外走岔了几次
A few accidental stop-offs along the way.
你从哪里弄的这袍子
Where did you get the robes?
12世纪君士坦丁堡
12th-century Constantinople.
我是个铁腕明君
I ruled firmly, but wisely.
-事情怎样了  -就那样嘛
- How did it go? - Oh, you know.
发出了警告  捐了个汉堡
Issued a warning, donated a burger,
顺了点文具
nicked some stationery.
-超灵  你知道了什么  -整个故事
- The Ghost, what have you got? - The whole story!
告诉我  我因为这个才把你重拼起来的
Fact me, baby, it's why I reassembled you.
不  先生  这不是真正的原因  对吗
No, sir, that's not the reason, is it?
你就别多想了
Just get on with it!
你把我从海卓弗斯王的身体上切下来
You cut me out of Hydroflax,
因为你担心自己会孤身一人
because you were worried you'd be lonely,
而我们都知道缘由  对吧
and we both know why, don't we?
可是  看看你  回避话题
But, oh, look at you, avoiding the subject!
我没有  我只是在试图拯救一个星球
I'm not avoiding anything, I'm just trying to save a planet.
你总是在话题变得严肃时这么干
Which is what you always do when the conversation turns serious.
乖宝宝
Good girl.
伦巴德夫人
Mrs Lombard?
-你看上去  很美  -你好像很惊讶
- You look... nice. - You look surprised.
不不不  只是
No, no, no, it's just that, well,
通常你会穿那件红色连身短裙  在你...
normally you wear the little red dress when you're, uh...
这是公事  格兰特
This is business, Grant.
只是公事
Strictly business.
所以...
So...
-我不会很晚回来的  -好
- I won't be late. - OK.
你好
Hi.
有什么不对吗
Is something wrong?
-你看上去很美  -你好像很惊讶
- You look nice. - You look surprised.
的确是
I am.
有点
A little.
他不该使用那些超能力  他保证过
He's not supposed to be using those powers. He made a promise.
怎么  就像是时间领主
What, like the Time Lord
保证过永不干涉
promise never to interfere in the affairs
其他种族或星球的事务那样吗
of other peoples or planets?
我可是把你的头给安回去了
I glued your head back on.
你得对我更尊重点
You should have a little bit more respect.
快跟上
Come on.
-我们在哪儿  -我们曾经在的地方
- Where are we? - Where we were,
但是还没去过
except not.
好吧
Right...
-东京分部  -对
- Tokyo branch. - Yep.
-有点空是不是  -我捣了点乱
- A bit empty, isn't it? - Yes, I created a distraction.
我搞得楼下到处都是宝可梦
I flooded downstairs with Pokemon.
你们不该在这里
You're not supposed to be in here.
我知道  真可怕
I know, it's terrible.
抱歉  我正尽可能阻止自己
Sorry, I'm doing everything I can to stop me.
-看到了没  -那是个信号对不对
- See that? - It's a signal, isn't it?
这是向宇宙发射的信号
It's a signal beaming into space.
从纽约分部也有这种信号发出
There was one from the New York office too.
在近地轨道上有什么东西
There's something in low orbit.
-我订了餐厅  -我
- I did book a restaurant. - I'm...
不太喜欢去餐厅
Not comfortable in restaurants.
我猜你穿成这样一定被不少人盯着看吧
I suppose you get a lot of stares, dressed like that.
这话还给你
Right back at you.
-你这样不冷吗  -没事
- Are you sure you're warm enough? - Yeah.
好吧  有点冷
OK, no.
-现在呢  -绝对好点了
- Now? - Yeah, definitely.
-对  近地轨道  -但你不能精确定位吗
- Yep, low orbit. - But you can't get a fix on it?
我在试  防护罩太厉害了
I'm trying, the shielding's too good.
-我们不能跟踪信号吗  -正在跟踪
- Can't we track the signals? - Tracking them now.
那你有什么超能力呢
So what powers do you have?
这个  基本的飞行
Well, basic flying,
-基本的超级力量  -基本的X透视吗
- basic super strength... - Basic X-ray vision?
没错
Yep.
这能力有没有很诱人
Is that ever tempting?
青春期的时候挺难熬的
Adolescence was difficult.
-怎么说  -就是持续时间更长
- In what sense? - It went on a lot longer.
有多长
How much longer?
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
我们正在就位
We're moving into position.
-不会很久  -已定位超灵所在地
- It won't be long now. - The Ghost is located.
外科医生行动
Action the surgeons.
就是那东西在接收和谐浅滩的信号
That's what Harmony Shoal is signalling to.
我们要不要上去看看
Shall we pop over and have a look?
-很确定上面没人  -你怎么知道
- Pretty sure no-one's on board. - How do you know?
-你扫描生命体了吗  -没有
- Did you scan for life forms? - No.
所有灯都关着呢
All the lights are off.
你有女朋友吗
Do you have a girlfriend?
男朋友呢
Boyfriend?
只是有那么一些猜测
Well, there has been speculation.
你可是穿着橡胶紧身衣在纽约飞
You do fly around New York dressed in rubber
胸口还印着一个大大的"G"字
with a big "G" on your chest.
这是不是有些太刻板印象化了
Are we very slightly stereotyping here?
我懂  你想保留一些个人隐私
I get it, there's some stuff you'd like to keep private.
难道是因为这面具告诉你的吗
Was it the mask that tipped you off?
你是怎么用双重身份生活的呢
How do you cope with your double life?
我并不特别  谁都有份白天的工作
I'm nothing special - everyone has a day job.
但你生活中一半的时间是做普通人
Come on, you spend half your time as a regular person...
我一直都是那样
I spend all my time that way.
而另一半时间则用来拯救世界
And the other half saving the world.
你怎么安排过来的
How do you cope?
那你是如何边工作边照顾宝宝的
How do you cope with a career and a baby?
你怎么知道我有个宝宝
How do you know I have a baby?
我...
I...
做了点调查
did my research.
我雇了保姆  你想说的是这个吧
I have a nanny, that's basically your answer.
是的  没错
Yes, of course.
-他现在就在楼下  -这样
- He's downstairs right now. - I see.
没错  我用的是"他"
And, yes, I said "He".
-没错  你是这么说的  -是的  没错
- Yes, you did. - Yes, I did.
这有什么问题吗
Is that a problem?
抱歉  只是你这样的人有时会嘲笑
I'm sorry, it's just that guys like you sometimes find it funny,
男人当保姆这事
a man being a nanny.
无意冒犯  弗莱彻小姐
With respect, Miss Fletcher,
像我这样的男人不多
there aren't too many guys like me.
像格兰特一样的男人也不多
There aren't too many guys like Grant either!
你还好么
You OK?
恕我失陪一下
Excuse me a minute.
舰桥在这边
Bridge is this way.
让开
Move.
我不是想暗示
I didn't mean to imply
你的朋友格兰特有问题
there's something wrong with your friend Grant.
不是所有人都能当超级英雄
Not everyone can be a superhero.
不是所有人都能当保姆
Not everyone can be a nanny!
抱歉
Sorry.
他现在就在楼下
He's downstairs right now
他计划去约会  不过取消了
and he was supposed to be on a date and he cancelled it
你知道我真正烦恼的是什么吗
and you know what's really bugging me about that?
他在和谁约会
Who is he dating?
我为什么会烦恼  我为什么在乎
Why is that bugging me? Why do I care?
我这是怎么了
What's wrong with me?
有些事或许我...
There's probably something I...
应该告诉你
ought to tell you.
格兰特
Grant.
完美的名字
The perfect name.
被我当成习惯的人
A man I take for granted.
说真的  如果你抬头看看
Really, if you could just look up about now...
永远在那里  永远和善  从不说谎
Always there, always kind, never lies.
我甚至骗他不会穿这件裙子
I even lied to him about this dress
可是我不认为他跟我说过一句谎话
but I don't think he's ever told a single lie to me,
一次也没有
not once,
任何事都没有
about anything.
-一次也没有  -很值得尊敬
- Not once. - That's very commendable.
晚上好
Good evening.
拜托不要妄动  否则要你朋友的命
Please, take no aggressive action, or your friend's life is over.
布洛克先生
Mr Brock?
-你想要什么  -和你一样  弗莱彻小姐
- What do you want here? - The same thing you do, Miss Fletcher.
他的身体
His body.
一堆破烂  对不
Bit rubbish, innit?
-什么也别碰  -不  这里很安全
- Don't touch anything. - No, it's quite safe,
就是艘货船
it's just a freighter.
-我说了别碰  -什...
- I said, don't touch. - Wh...
就在这  核反应核心
It's here, the reactor core.
正在临界值运转
It's cycling at critical.
有人重新布线了
Someone's been rewiring.
这不再是艘飞船了
This isn't a ship any more.
它是个巨型炸弹
It's a giant bomb.
我出去了...
Just going to move out...
博士
Doctor!
不过是安保机器人而已
They're security drones, that's all.
他们要炸弹做什么
So what do they want a bomb for?
炸弹还能做什么
What does anybody want a bomb for?
他们肯定是想征服地球  不是炸飞掉
Surely they want to conquer the Earth, not blow it up.
用这个可炸不掉地球...
You couldn't blow up the Earth with this...
不过可以抹平一座城市
But you could wipe out a city.
-说到点上了  干得好  -什么点
- Good point, well made! - What point?
纽约不是首都
New York, it's not a capital city,
-你说的很对  -我没明白
- you're quite right. - Oh... I don't understand.
把这艘飞船扔到纽约  会发生什么
What if you dropped this ship on New York, what would happen?
核反应核心分裂  纽约被蒸发掉
The reactor core would split and New York would vaporise.
不是所有建筑
Not all of it.
不是所有建筑  纳多尔
Not all of it, Nardole.
记得那个吓人的德国小个子说的话么
Remember what he said, the scary little German fella?
这栋建筑可以承受
This building can withstand a blast
四倍于核爆力量的爆炸
up to four times the strength of a nuclear explosion.
这太好了  非常巧妙
This is very good, very meta.
你明白了么
Did you understand?
你们精心策划了一次外星袭击
You're stage-managing an alien attack
尽管外星人已经登上了地球
when the aliens have already landed.
-不过为什么呢  -为了接下来的事
- But why? - Because of what happens next.
等到所有人都认为地球遭到来自太空的袭击
When everyone thinks that the Earth is being attacked from space,
-会发生什么  -大范围恐慌
- what then? - Mass panic.
说到恐慌
Speaking of panic!
别担心  门被三重死锁封住了
Don't worry, it's triple-deadlock-sealed.
至少能撑十分钟
It'll hold for at least ten minutes.
民众会恐慌  对的
The people will panic, yes.
但是世界领导呢
But what about the world leaders?
总统和国王  首相和将军们
The presidents and kings, the prime ministers and generals?
他们会做什么
What will they do?
当战争开始  有钱人总会做什么
What do the rich old men always do when the fighting starts?
他们会找到最安全的地方藏起来
They'll find the safest place to hide themselves away
让所有年轻人去送死
and send all their young people to die.
现在每座首都最安全的地方在哪
And where's the safest place in every capital city now?
纽约的哪座建筑还没倒下
What's the only part of New York still standing?
和谐浅滩
Harmony Shoal.
纽约不是首都
New York isn't a capital city.
而是橱窗
It's a shop window.
"当世界陷入危机  和我们藏在一起"
"When the world is in danger, come hide with us."
和谐浅滩会为
Harmony Shoal will open its doors
吓坏了的世界领导敞开大门
to the terrified leaders of the world.
他们会一路小跑
And they will come running.
几个小时后  每位政客和总司令
A few hours later, every politician and commander-in-chief
头上都会装上拉链
will have a zip in their head.
头骨里坐着一个外星人
An alien sitting inside their skull.
只要一天的恐慌
In one day of terror,
行星地球的领导权
the executive authority of Planet Earth
就会交到和谐浅滩上
will pass to Harmony Shoal.
好计划  我喜欢
It's a good plan, I like it.
为什么我们这边的人从来想不出这样的计划
How come our side never gets plans like that?
人类完全没有计划
The humans have no plan at all.
这点你说错了
That's where you're wrong.
他们每次都有同一个计划
They have the same plan they always have.
-什么计划  -我
- What plan? - Me.
-别这么做  -抱歉
- Don't do that. - Sorry.
手术很快而且没有痛感
The operation is swift and quite painless.
你知道我这是和罐子里的同事说的吧
You realize I'm talking to my colleague in the jar?
你会发现我要比
You'll find me a lot harder
你之前的那些受害者更难切开
to cut open than your previous victims.
和谐浅滩花了五年来征服你们的星球
Harmony Shoal have been conquering your world for five years.
-别的不行但我们有耐心  -超灵
- Whatever our faults, we have the virtue of patience. - Ghost!
别担心我  做你该做的
Don't worry about me, do what you've got to do.
-你敢轻举妄动我们就杀了她  -别听他的
- Do anything at all and we'll kill her. - Don't listen to him!
把面具拿掉  我喜欢看他们的脸
Remove the mask. I like to see their faces.
我十分抱歉
I'm truly sorry.
从好的一面来看  至少我能杀了你
On the bright side, at least I get to kill you.
不  你不能
No, you can't!
这就是只有一个人质的不便之处
That's the trouble with one hostage.
你杀了我  他回来的唯一理由就会是复仇
You kill me, the only reason he'll come back is for revenge.
-你真的想试试吗  -一个人质
- You really want to deal with that? - One hostage?
楼下是不是有个小孩
Isn't there a child downstairs?
谁都不许碰那个孩子
Nobody touches that child.
你是谁
And who are you?
我是孩子的保姆
I'm the nanny.
离开控制板  博士
Stand away from the controls, Doctor.
任何进行干扰的企图
Any attempt to interfere with them
-都会立刻触发进攻  -我发现了
- will precipitate the attack immediately. - Yes, I see that!
非常聪明  我有个问题  既然我在这里
Very clever. One question, as long as I'm here -
-为什么你还没有动手  -等时机到了
- why haven't you done it already? - When the time is right,
-我就会立马动手  -你这话有意思
- there will be no delay. - Oh, you told me something there!
你的话能给我帮上忙  你不该说漏嘴的
You told me something useful, you shouldn't have done that.
我告诉你什么了
What did I tell you?
你告诉了我现在还不是时候
You told me that the time is currently wrong.
这个笑容
It's the smile.
我不喜欢这个笑容
I don't like the smile!
达摩克利斯之剑就悬在纽约上面
The Sword of Damocles hanging over New York!
我毁不了也动不了它更无法阻止它掉下去
I can't destroy it, I can't remove it, I can't stop it falling.
-我能做的只有一件事  -什么
- There's only one thing I can do. - What?
出乎意料的事
The unexpected!
在一个
The thing about being in
满是按钮和开关的房间里能做的
a room full of buttons and switches is...
我爱按钮和开关
I love buttons and switches!
-停下来  -你在做什么
- Don't! - What are you doing?
你在做什么
What are you doing?!
推进器已开动
'Thrusters engaged.'
下一站纽约
Next stop New York!
一起说  哇哦
Say, "Wheeee!"
放下护盾  准备迎接撞击
Lower shields! Brace for impact!
纽约正遭受攻击
New York is under attack.
弗莱彻小姐  我现在似乎有三个人质了
It occurs to me, Miss Fletcher, I now have three hostages.
你为什么不把枪指着我
Why don't you point the gun at me?
有什么不同吗
What difference would it make?
而且
Besides,
我觉得她才是超灵会来救的人
this is the one the Ghost will come for, I think.
超灵
Ghost!
你听得到我吗
Can you hear me?
你有超级听觉吗
Do you have super hearing?
我会杀了她
I'm going to kill her.
我现在就要杀了她
I'm going to kill her right now!
停下来  你会毁了纽约的
Stop! You're going to destroy New York!
当然不会
Of course not!
现在炸弹装上了  防护罩也没了
Now the bomb is arming, the shields are down...
-救命  -我们能用塔迪斯
- Help! - We can use the TARDIS...
操纵控制板然后把飞船转向宇宙
to hijack the controls and divert it into space!
没有炸弹
No bomb,
没有计划
no plan,
没有问题
no problem!
不  等等
No, wait!
那些东西还在外面
Those things are out there!
飞船要坠毁了  他们不会来关心我们的
The ship is crashing! They're not going to be worrying about us!
-计划B  -博士
- OK, plan B... - Doctor!
-救我  -你会没事的
- Help me! - Oh, you'll be fine!
等到你被勒死
The ship will have blown up
飞船早就已经炸了
long before you've been strangled to death!
-计划B是什么  -我不知道
- And what's plan B?! - I have no idea,
但等我想到的时候一定会非常欣慰
but it's going to be a very big relief when I think of it.
你完全是疯了
You are completely out of your mind!
说点别人不知道的
How is that news to anyone?
我知道你想她  但你不能就写首诗吗
I know you miss her, but couldn't you just write a poem?
太棒了  控制板锁住了
Excellent! The controls are locked,
但它还能派上点用
but they've still got a little bit of give.
这意味着我能瞄准
It means I can take aim.
-朝什么瞄准  -纽约
- At what?! - New York.
只有一次机会  但一次就够了
There's exactly one chance, and one is all you need.
不  不要...
No! No-o-o...
不  不  来得太早了
No. No, it's too soon.
格兰特  格兰特  我是博士
Grant! Grant! This is the Doctor!
你是地球上唯一一个
You are the only living thing on Earth
能听见这个频率的人
that can hear this frequency.
抬头看  我们正朝着你来
Look up! We're coming right at you.
如果这个玩意撞到了地上  那纽约就完了
If that thing hits the ground, then New York is finished!
看你的了
Over to you.
伦巴德女士  请趴下
Mrs Lombard, please get down.
-纳多尔  -怎么了
- Nardole! - Yeah?
准备迎接撞击
Brace for impact!
纳多尔
Nardole.
-纳多尔  -还有一件事  给我发黄包车
- Nardole! - OK, one more, but text me a rickshaw...
纳多尔  成功了
Nardole, it worked!
反应堆芯没有分裂
The reactor core didn't split!
-为什么没有  -减震器
- Why not? - Shock absorber.
伦巴德女士  我觉得从许多方面来说
Mrs Lombard, I realize in many ways it would have been better
我最好解释一下今晚前一些时候的事情
to have mentioned something about this earlier in the evening,
但请别扇我
but, please, don't slap me.
我想我现在正举着一个巨大的炸弹
I think I'm holding a giant bomb.
你看那儿  看看他
There, on you go, take a look at him.
这就是为什么你们毫无获胜的可能
That's why you don't stand a chance.
想知道为什么吗
You want to know why?
他其实是左撇子
He's actually left-handed.
抱歉  本能反应  我不能弄丢这个
Sorry, instinct, I couldn't let go of this.
你俩如果要搞激情戏
If you two are about to get excited,
或许可以先摆脱那架飞船
maybe you could get rid of that spaceship first.
你知道吗
You know what?
我更喜欢你穿着超级英雄的衣服
I think I prefer you in your superhero costume.
现在去换有点困难
It's a bit difficult for me to change right now.
我可以帮你
I'll do it for you.
格兰特
Grant!
格兰特  记住  当你
Grant! Remember, when you're...
完事的时候
finished,
把那东西扔向太阳
throw that thing into the sun.
詹妮弗还在楼下
Jennifer's still downstairs!
那么  博士
So, Doctor...
-你觉得这事儿结束了吗  -是的
- ..You think this is over? - Yeah.
你的炸弹没了  你的计划泡汤了
Your bomb's gone, your plan's finished.
看  那是UNIT  正要关闭你们的总部
And look, there's UNIT, on the way to close your head office.
就好像有人向他们泄露了信息
It's almost like they've been tipped off.
和谐浅滩的复仇在五恒星系统中
The vengeance of Harmony Shoal is known and feared
-是人尽皆知的可怕  -是吗
- throughout the five star systems! - Ooh! Is it
真的吗  我想待在这听你说戏
Is it really? Well, I'd like to stick around and listen,
但是今晚发生的事太多了
but it's been a very long night.
再加上有人需要换尿布
Also, someone needs changing.
这里淘气的可不只有你一个人
You're not the only one that's full of it.
我们走  我们走
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
-下来  -放开我
- Down here now! - Get off of me!
-你们找到他时就这样了吗  -是的长官
- And he was like this when you found him? - Yes, sir.
在这里等着
Wait here.
我联系一下奥斯古德
I'm putting a call into Osgood.
-所以  不再当超灵了吗  -不当了
- So, no more Ghost, then? - Nah, laid to rest.
-你确定吗  -我当然确定
- Are you sure? - Yeah, of course I'm sure.
人生可不是漫画  对吧  博士
I mean, life's not a comic book, right, Doctor?
这问题不应该问我
Possibly I'm not the right person to ask.
万一又出什么事呢
What if something happens?
万一世界又有危险呢
What if the whole world is in danger?
那或许我该留着那衣服
Well, you know, maybe I'll keep the outfit, then.
你知道  以防万一
You know, just in case.
世界没事的  我离开了一阵  但我回来了
The world will be fine. I've been away for a while, but I'm back.
发生什么事我都能应对
I'll take care of anything that comes up.
-你离开了  -24年
- You were away? - Huh! 24 years.
今晚真精彩
What a night.
你去了哪里
Where did you go?
问得不对
Wrong question.
她叫什么
What was her name?
我肯定我还有事要忙  我得走了
I'm sure that I must be busy, I better go.
-你还好吗  -好好好  我很好
- You OK? - Yes, yes, yes, I'm OK.
事情终有尽头
Things end.
就是这样
That's all.
万事皆有尽头
Everything ends.
结局总是伤感
And it's always sad.
但一切又将迎来新的轮回
But everything begins again too,
新生事物总会带来喜悦
and that's always happy.
要快乐
Be happy.
其他的我来处理就行
I'll look after everything else.
-纳多尔  -博士
- Nardole. - Hey, Doctor?
要说真话
Keep it real.
她的名字叫瑞雯・宋
Her name was River Song.
他们曾有过一段快乐的时光
They were together for a while and they were very happy.
然后她去世了
And then she died,
很久以前的事了
a long time ago,
-在一座图书馆  -你确定他不会有事吗
- in a library. - Are you sure he's going to be all right?
他可是博士
He's the Doctor.
他很勇敢  也很傻
He's very brave and he's very silly
我想他会难过一阵
and I think, for a time, he's going to be very sad.
但我保证  最终
But I promise, in the end,
他会好好的
he'll be all right.
我会确保他好好的
I'll make sure of it.
回见
Bye!
你从没细说
You never explained.
他到底是谁
Who exactly is he?
什么博士
Doctor who?
神秘
Doctor...
博士
Mysterio.
我是比尔  我是盛薯条的
I'm Bill. I serve chips.
他是个教授  或是个讲师
He's a professor. Or a lecturer.
而我则叫他...
Or as I call him...
什么博士
Doctor what?
现在我们四处旅行
And now we go everywhere.
-它就像是一...  -宇宙飞船
- It's like a... - Spaceship.
厨房
Kitchen!
任何空间
Any space...
我们在哪  地球在哪边  戴立克是什么
Where are we? Which way's Earth? What's a Dalek?
我能用一下厕所吗
Can I use the toilet?
任何时间
Any time...
进来
Get in!
我眼中的一切  如今都已不同
And now I see everything... differently.
消灭
Exterminate!
-我们在哪  -说简单点就是在一场战争中
- Where are we? - Basically in the middle of a war.
实际没有听起来那么糟
And it's not as bad as it sounds!
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
我会拯救你们  而在那之后
I will save all your lives and when I do,
你会耗尽余生好奇我是谁
you will spend the rest of them wondering who I was.
你是疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
是的  完全疯了  但不是最近的事
Yes, completely, but that's not a recent thing.